<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HACKFIT2021</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_home">Home</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_diary">Diary</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_music">Music</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_blogs">Blogs</string>
    <string name="journal_title">Title</string>
    <string name="storage_permission_text">This app needs access to your storage.</string>
    <string name="great_text">Great!</string>
    <string name="how_feel">How do you feel today?</string>
    <string name="good_text">Good</string>
    <string name="ok_text">Ok</string>
    <string name="bad_text">Bad</string>
    <string name="terrible_text">Terrible</string>
    <string name="blog_1">Anxiety and depression are two of the most common mental health conditions we see. And though they’re frequently confused, they’re actually different classes of disorders. Some of the confusion stems from an overlap in symptoms and in the fact that they often co-occur. But despite sharing some symptoms, there is a significant difference between anxiety and depression in the actual definition of each condition.

On a high level, anxiety involves excessive worrying or stress about the outcome of a situation. Depression, on the other hand, is a mood disorder that causes overwhelming feelings of sadness or apathy.

We’ll dive into the key differences below and review each mental health condition in more detail.

What Is the Difference Between Anxiety and Depression?
Part of the reason why anxiety vs depression can be difficult for many people to identify is that there are overlapping symptoms in the two conditions. Also, keep in mind that many people diagnosed with major depressive disorder may also have an anxiety disorder. In fact, nearly half of all people diagnosed with depression are also diagnosed with an anxiety disorder.

So, what is the difference between anxiety and depression?

While there are many common symptoms between anxiety and depression — such as fatigue, changes in appetite, and difficulty concentrating — there are also some blatant differences. For example, excessive worry is more common with anxiety, whereas thoughts of suicide are more prevalent with depression.

Anxiety and depression also fall into different classifications of disorders. Anxiety is its own class, and depression is a separate mood disorder. Finally, another difference between the two conditions is that they’re sometimes treated with different medications.

To best understand the differences listed above, it’s important to review these disorders in-depth.</string>
</resources>